

EMAIL

jacob.kim.johnson@gmail.com

wordstosong.me

LINKEDIN

in/jacobkimjohnson

DUONE

(608)790-7675

LOCATION

Los Angeles, CA

I'm a UX/UI designer and visual designer with experience in industries including start-ups, nonprofits, and tech, which has given me the distinct ability to examine situations and consider strategies from different perspectives. I have a deep passion for crafting elegant and engaging interfaces, and my creativity, empathy, critical thinking, and collaborative nature have been beneficial in helping me understand user behaviors and motivations, as well as make thoughtful decisions. Those insights have allowed me be more open-minded as I figure out the details, while focusing on the big picture.

**JACOB KIM JOHNSON** 

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **UX/UI Designer** TiM/Media Services Los Angeles, CA Jan. 2019 – Present

- As the senior designer, conceived user interfaces to create and improve experiences on a SaaS application platform
- Using Agile methodology, collaborated with project managers, engineers, and stakeholders to simplify and solve complex problems throughout the application
- Created wireframes and interactive prototypes of designs
- Collaborated with client support team and met with clients to help identify and understand pain points within the application
- Developed brand and design guidelines to ensure consistency and integrity within the application
- Designed and created visual elements within the application

UX/UI Designer, Graphic Designer, and Web Developer Self-employed Los Angeles, CA Aug. 2017 – Present

- Crafted user experiences by designing and developing user-centric, mobile-first web apps from scratch (using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript)
- Created UX deliverables including wireframes, prototypes, and user flows.
- Consulted with organizations on how to improve overall user experience
- Collaborated with web developers to provide designs that are in line with current and effective web practices
- Refined typography execution with font pairings, hierarchy, and spacing
- Refined aspects of visual design, like color theory and visual hierarchy/spacing
- Designed and created graphics for logos and web content
- Researched ongoing design trends, both in UX/UI and visual composition

UX/UI Designer, Graphic Designer, and Web Content Coordinator CBE International Minneapolis, MN Jul. 2014 – Sep. 2017

- Helped plan, research, test, and implement website functionality and design to improve user experience for conversion-oriented interface
- Created wireframes and mockups of web pages for updates and redesigns
- Created UX user personas and conceptualized journey maps
- Operated under an Agile-like iterative and continuous design process, and met with developers on a daily-to-weekly basis to work through design specifications
- Designed logo concepts for the organization's main brand and blog
- Created graphic images for internal (e.g. web headers) and external (e.g. advertisements) purposes
- Designed and edited printed marketing materials and book covers/layouts
- Coordinated with all departments to ensure brand and visual consistency
- Edited and managed web content with Drupal CMS and HTML/CSS
- Improved social media strategies to be more visual, better suit reader interest, and increase interaction

Marketing Specialist (Contractor) CATS Software, Inc. Minneapolis, MN Apr. 2014 – Jul. 2014

- Researched user experience and competitors to create strategies to improve
- Experienced Agile methodology with daily standup meetings and JIRA for project management
- Created icons, graphics, and cartoons as companions to blog articles and social media posts
- Wrote blog posts and managed social media accounts and helped facilitate conversation for start-up organization

### **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Arts Luther College Decorah, IA Graduated May 2010

- Major: Business Management
- Minor: Psychology
- Emphasis: Marketing

# Certificate

Minneapolis Community and Technical College Minneapolis, MN Completed Dec. 2014

- Graphic Design
- Web Design

### **SKILLED WITH**

- Sketch •
- Invision
- Illustrator
- Photoshop
  - InDesign
    - Zeplin